
export const quizQuestions_4 = {
  questions: [
    {
      question: 'What is the primary purpose of functional components in React?',
      choices: [
        'To manage state in a component.',
        'To provide a way to extend component behavior.',
        'To encapsulate reusable UI elements.',
        'To define class-based components.',
      ],
      correctAnswer: 'To encapsulate reusable UI elements.',
    },
    {
      question: 'How do you pass data from a parent component to a child component in React?',
      choices: [
        'Using the `setState` method.',
        'Through the `this.props` object.',
        'By directly modifying the child component state.',
        'Data cannot be passed from parent to child components.',
      ],
      correctAnswer: 'Through the `this.props` object.',
    },
    {
      question: 'In React, what is the purpose of the `props` object?',
      choices: [
        'To define internal state within a component.',
        'To manage component lifecycle methods.',
        'To store information about the component hierarchy.',
        'To receive data from parent components.',
      ],
      correctAnswer: 'To receive data from parent components.',
    },
    {
      question: 'How can you pass a callback function as a prop to a child component?',
      choices: [
        'Wrap the callback function in curly braces.',
        'Use the `this.callback` syntax.',
        'Callback functions cannot be passed as props.',
        'Enclose the callback function in quotes.',
      ],
      correctAnswer: 'Wrap the callback function in curly braces.',
    },
    {
      question: 'What is the purpose of the `children` prop in React?',
      choices: [
        'To represent the child components of a parent.',
        'To define default values for component props.',
        'To access and render the content between opening and closing tags of a component.',
        'To pass additional styling information to child components.',
      ],
      correctAnswer: 'To access and render the content between opening and closing tags of a component.',
    },
    {
      question: 'How do you handle events in a functional component in React?',
      choices: [
        'By defining event handlers inside the render method.',
        'Functional components cannot handle events.',
        'By using the `this.handleEvent` syntax.',
        'By passing callback functions as props.',
      ],
      correctAnswer: 'By passing callback functions as props.',
    },
    {
      question: 'What is the role of the `key` prop in React?',
      choices: [
        'To uniquely identify an element in an array of components.',
        'To set the initial state of a component.',
        'To define a CSS class for a component.',
        'To access the current state of a component.',
      ],
      correctAnswer: 'To uniquely identify an element in an array of components.',
    },
    {
      question: 'How can you conditionally render content in a React component based on a prop?',
      choices: [
        'By using the `setState` method.',
        'By modifying the `props` object directly.',
        'Conditionally rendering is not possible in functional components.',
        'By using JavaScript expressions in JSX.',
      ],
      correctAnswer: 'By using JavaScript expressions in JSX.',
    },
    {
      question: 'What is the purpose of the `propTypes` property in a functional component?',
      choices: [
        'To define the internal state of the component.',
        'To specify the expected data types of the component props.',
        'To set the default values for props.',
        'PropTypes are not applicable to functional components.',
      ],
      correctAnswer: 'To specify the expected data types of the component props.',
    },
    {
      question: 'How can you destructure props in a functional component?',
      choices: [
        'props = {};',
        '{ props } = {};',
        'const { props } = {};',
        'const { prop1, prop2 } = props;',
      ],
      correctAnswer: 'const { prop1, prop2 } = props;',
    },
  ]}